globenewswire.com 2015-06-29

# Privacy Statement: About GlobeNewswire

## GlobeNewswire's Privacy Statement

This privacy statement covers all Web sites operated by GlobeNewswire ("GlobeNewswire"), including all sites in the globenewswire.com, primezone.com, topicnewschannels.com and irconnect.com domains.

Because we are committed to your privacy, we are disclosing our information practices that pertain to the collection and use of information that may uniquely identify a person, business, organization or other entity.

Although GlobeNewswire collects a variety of information, we do not sell, barter, exchange or otherwise provide any of the information we collect to any third party, except as follows:

  1. GlobeNewswire operates a news release distribution network whereby we distribute the content of news releases issued by our registered members to a wide variety of third parties. This information is limited to the actual news releases (approved by the originating organization) and metadata describing the news release such as company name, stock symbol and category codes.
  2. GlobeNewswire operates an investor relations Web site service that provides for the distribution of news and financial information regarding publicly traded companies. All information distributed via this service is either public knowledge or explicitly preapproved for distribution by our registered members.
  3. We may be required to provide information to a law enforcement agency, but only as the result of a request relating to a specific legal proceeding.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact our Customer Support Department. If you do not receive a response within 24 hours, please contact our Customer Service Center by calling 310-642-6930.

## Information Collection and Use

### Information Collection

GlobeNewswire is the sole owner of the information collected on our sites. We collect different information for visitors and registered users at several different points on our Web site.

### Member Registration

In order to use GlobeNewswire's news release distribution, Web site hosting or related services, an organization must register as a member. Member registration is conducted via a secure, online form, protected through the use of the SSL encryption protocol.

An off-line (paper-based) registration form is also available upon request. Using this method, the paper form is faxed to us, and GlobeNewswire staff enter the information into our computer database system.

As part of the member registration process, individuals are encouraged, but not required, to provide telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, postal addresses, credit card data and other information. Individuals are also assigned a user name and password.

We **never** require a user to provide a social security number.

### Visitor Registration

A visitor to a GlobeNewswire Web site may be prompted to register to access certain features of a Web site, or to receive information via e-mail. The information requested through these registration forms will be used only for the purpose stated in the registration forms.

## Information Use

### Third Party Advertising

We do not currently include advertising, in any form, on any of our sites.

### Profile

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, transparent images, or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that detail their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the user's personally identifiable information to improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site. We do not share your profile with other third parties.

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

By setting a cookie on our sites, users do not have to log in more than once, thereby saving time while on our sites. If users reject the cookie, they may not be able to login to certain areas of our sites.

### Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

### Transparent Images

We employ a software technology called transparent images, that helps us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. We use extremely small, transparent images with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, that are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that transparent images are invisible on the page and are very small, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. In some instances, transparent images are tied to users' personally identifiable information. In particular, we use transparent images in our HTML-based e-mails to let us know which e-mails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications. Users may opt out of these e-mails. Please see the opt out section.

## Communications from our Sites

### Special Offers and Updates

We send all new members a welcoming e-mail or an e-mail to verify password and user name. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and opt out sections.

### Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and e-mail address. Out of respect for our users' privacy we provide a way to opt out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service-related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily unavailable for maintenance we might send users an e-mail alerting them to this fact. Generally, users may not opt out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Users may opt out of these communications. Please see our Choice and opt out section.

### Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and address issues relating to their account. We reply via e-mail or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

## Sharing

### Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on GlobeNewswire.

### Third Party Advertisers

We do not currently include advertising, in any form, on any of our sites.

### Service Providers

We use a third-party credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. This company only retains sufficient information to process an individual credit card transaction.

## Choice and Opt out

Our users are given the opportunity to opt out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our sites at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an opt out mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their e-mail address off of our lists.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt out of receiving these communications by replying to the unsubscribe link at the end of the e-mail message. Users can contact us via e-mail to opt out.

## Links

GlobeNewswire's Web sites contain links to other sites. Please be aware that GlobeNewswire is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by GlobeNewswire Web sites.

## Security

GlobeNewswire takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via our Web sites, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the SSL, an industry-standard encryption technology. While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when users are viewing and unprotected page.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also endeavor to protect user information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to regain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up to date on our security and privacy practices.

## Correcting, Updating, Deleting, Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as ZIP code, phone, e-mail or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done via our Customer Service Center or by e-mailing our customer support.

## Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement on the home page and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it; and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users via e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with our sites or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web sites notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice, we will also e-mail users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.
